<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Manabu</title>
    <link>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Manabu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ROS connection between multiple machines on LAN</title>
      <link>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/ros-multiple-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/ros-multiple-machines/</guid>
      <description>I have an orangepi zero that I want to connect to a ROS instance running on my desktop to play around with manual control on PX4. I have followed some instructions here but they appear not to work for me. The orangepi always says that there is no roscore running. I searched and searched and I came across this page that seems to provide correct instructions. I did it like in the below-mentioned procedure and the orange pi seems to recognize the ROS instance running on my desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding images in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/add-images-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/add-images-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Adding images in Hugo I had a lot of trouble adding images in Hugo and searched a lot on the internet and finally solved the problem. The thanks go to the comment under an issue.
The secret is to store the images in the static folder and also follow the correct directory structure. If we take this page as an example, the images are added into static\posts\qtcreator-ros\ folder to mimic the search path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QtCreator with ROS</title>
      <link>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/qtcreator-ros/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/qtcreator-ros/</guid>
      <description>I have tried many IDEs and found that QtCreator is the one that I like. So I wanted to setup QtCreator for ROS development.
Prerequisites Installing ROS I assume that you have already installed ROS on your operating system. If not you can follow these instructions
Installing QtCreator An open-sourced version of QtCreator can be downloaded from here. From here you can only download QtCreator IDE without downloading the Qt framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Typesetting</title>
      <link>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/mathtypesetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parzival2.github.io/manabu/posts/mathtypesetting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematical notation in a Hugo project can be enabled by using third party JavaScript libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
